hey guys rexin here welcome to another
crash course guide this time for shke
keeper so I'll just head straight into
what you should do for her rotation and
how she functions so first things first
you start with her ultimate and then you
simply intro the next character in and
then you intro your third character in
and then you finish off with another
intro back to short keeper to finish the
whole cycle and then you rinse repeat so
let me show you what I mean I'm just
going to engage these wolves I have all
of their concerto ready now I'll press
ultimate
so notice how it's white or blue I'll
intro Arina
in and now it's
purple and then I'll intro y l and now
it's gold so this is the final
version and then I'll intro short Keeper
in while it's
active and this
happens and that's it that's basically
what you should be doing for her
so for her forte it's really similar to
ba where you get gauged simply by
attacking like this and then when it's
full you either do jump attack or heavy
attack to spend it and it'll turn into a
vacuum should pull the enemies and
that's pretty much it so you can do like
this full combo five and then you jump
and attack suspend it you can also get
your gauge simply by doing an air combo
opener like this
and then you heavy attack or jump attack
to spend all five gauges to pull them
like that and another thing to note is
that if you do the air version she can
skip straight to combo two like
this like
[Music]
that so that's pretty much it for her
forte it's really simple the other thing
to note is that if you've seen the
trailer she can turn into a butterfly so
simply press and hold basic attack and
she will get gauge over time like this
you see the bottom here those blue gauge
will translate to her main yellow gauge
once I exit from here like this see full
gauge however the butterfly skill you
mostly only use it during PVE during
exploration you don't really need to use
it during attack during combat I mean
and then that's it for her forte now
let's talk about her ultimate if you
look over here resonance Liberation the
white ring that you saw earlier that's
called outer Stellar realm and then when
you do one intro with a character it
turns into inner Stellar realm and then
when you do one more intro the one I did
with yinin and then it became gold
that's called superal Stellar realm so
I'm just going to short it into outer
inner and super Stellar realm so that
it's easier for you to understand so
what happens here is that when she cast
the first ultimate everybody gets a
regen every 3 seconds that's it and then
when you use the next character to intro
and turn it into an inner Stellar realm
that character will gain a crit rate up
to 12.5% based on her energy regen so if
you see the math over here uh tldr you
need
250% energy Regen to get 12.5% and then
for the next character intro you'll get
super Stellar realm so on top of crit
rate you'll also get crit damage up to
25% so short keeper is basically a crit
support as for her outro she also gives
15% damage M similar to Verina so short
keeper gives damage M and crit support
I'll demonstrate her ultimate and intro
and show you the differences starting
with short keeper again ultimate and
this ultimate is only going to give
regen every 3 seconds it's just healing
so white ultimate is just healing and
then intro the next character now it's
purple so look purple is crit rate so
Verina now has 48% crit rate Yin has 79%
crit rate it was uh 69 before
nice and now I'll intro yinin in the
ring is going to turn gold that's the
super Stellar realm and then it's going
to give her crit rate and crit damage so
79 224 let me intro yinin
in now it's
go see 79
245 so now that it's goal logically
always put your DPS on the third slot so
they benefit from both crit rate and
crit damage and then once you've done
all your damage you can finish it off
with another short keeper intro while
the ultimate is still active and that
will finish the loop so I'm just going
to pretend that I've done all my DPS and
then I'll intro short keeper like
this that's the special
intro for the skills we'll skip normal
resonance Forte and resonance Liberation
because I've already talked about that
well the one we want to look at is intro
skill and over here Enlightenment is her
normal intro the one you want to look at
is discernment discernment is that big
intro that you saw earlier when super
nural Stellar realm is generated short
keeper first intro skill triggered in
its duration will be replaced with
discernment and discernment will restore
HP to all members and deal damage and
this damage is guaranteed crit
guaranteed crit and is scaled from
resonance Liberation damage so this uh
discernment can only be triggered once
every Ultimate and look at her scaling
discernment is scaled from HP however
the first four tabs here they're all
scaled from attack for her Attack Base
moves like normal attack is scaled from
Attack resonance skill also skill from
Attack Forte circuit also skill from
Attack this is basically a trap no need
to pump attack stats for her just go all
into HP so for short keeper just go all
in HP so that her special intro damage
increases since it's guaranteed crit
this will be your main source of damage
from short keeper and then we look at
inherent skill number one this is
insurance basically uh if someone's
going to die she'll save them and
inherent number two when resonator on
the field is within the range of her
ultimate her energy energy regen is
increased by 10% and Rover's energy
regen is also increased by 10% if Rover
is on a team so you want to level this
one so that she gets more energy regen
especially when you're not close to 250%
this one will push you closer to 250% so
tldr if you want to level short keeper
skills I highly recommend leaving normal
resonance skill Forte and Liberation at
four 4 to six since those are cheap you
don't really need levels on them more
level would just mean more healing and
slight increase in like a negligible
damage so either you leave it at level
one if you're broke or level four or
level six and all in all in into intro
you can put 10 into intro the rest just
leave it and as for the top uh inherent
skills just go for the first two
inherent skills here and HP increase on
the sides more HP more damage healing
percent is subjective if you've got the
Mets to spare then yeah why not just
level healing however you can leave
these left as so for her Echo I would
highly recommend policy of no return
that is the new echo of this patch
because uh when you tap this echo's
effect short keeper will get 10% energy
regen and then the following all team
members will get 10% attack for 20
seconds and you can also hold the echo
skills to do her JoJo punch like this
well this this could be potentially
helpful to build ultimate for you if you
have trouble building residence
Liberation so simply just hold and
release it consumes stamina
like that so that will be for the four
cost policy of no return and then for
three cost highly recommend energy and
for the one cost go for HP and obviously
it's going to be the healing set now for
her four cost I personally use crit
damage since her discernment skill is
guaranteed crit anyway I'm just going to
pump all in into crit damage and for
three cost I highly recommend just
leaving it at energy regen because she's
going to need all that energy Regen to
push her closer to uh 250% % energy
regen 230 is also good enough 230 with
the effect of her Echo and also her
inherent skill 10% from each and for the
substats energy regen obviously and then
you can also go for crit damage and
resonance Liberation if you want more
damage on her discernment and also HP
both percentage and uh flat HP are also
good she doesn't really need crit rate
since it's guaranteed crit anyway now
let's talk about her weapon so I have
her weapon here at rank five so if you
want to see rank one it's basically half
of all the values here so 77% energy
regen this really helps for pushing her
to 250% energy regen uh HP increased
from 12 to 24% and then 8 to 16 conal
energy whenever she cast ultimate every
20 seconds cool down and also casting a
resonance skill that heals increases uh
attack by 14 to 20% for the whole party
so this will not be usable for Vina
because Vina's e skill is pure damage
healing only comes from using her gauge
but this will work on B in the event
that you want to use this on B however
we'll compare this to the other
alternative which is variation so if
you're f2p or low spender and you have
variation variation is a really good
candidate instead of rolling for her
signature weapon you can just opt to use
variation variation also gives energy
regen up to 52% at level 90 and rank one
to five also gives 8 to 16 conal energy
this is the same scaling it's also 8 to
16 except variation is four star so it's
potentially easier to get it to rank
five in the long run and the other big
difference is that variation is
triggered from resonance skill so it's a
lot easier to build her concerto since
you only need to press uh e skill
meanwhile her signature only gets
concerto on resonance Liberation so if
you have uh no ultimate ready it's
really hard to benefit from this so yeah
you can see that variation is a really
good alternative however if you don't
have variation you can opt to use the
crafted four star over here rectifier 25
solely for the energy regen main stat
and it's free to craft all you need is
materials or you can also use combat
Flare from the gacha which boosts HP as
the main stat so comat flare or the
crafted fourstar followed by variation
followed by signature weapon so if you
already have a really good variation you
can consider skipping her signature for
cost reasons and now let's talk about
her resonance chain the sequences so for
short keeper I recommend the stopping
point to be either s0 or S2 or S3 or S6
skip four and five if you're going to go
past three straight away just go for six
because there's no point stopping at
four and five so we'll just go through
each of them one by one so at S1 sterle
realm her ultimate the range of the
healing and buff is increased by 150%
and the duration is extended so that
goes from 30 to 40 seconds and casting
intro skill discernment no longer ends
the Stellar realm that means that when
it's gold and you use a short keeper
special in the gold Aura still stays so
she still benefits from the crit and
crit damage buff so this is S1 the
reason why S2 is so good is really
simple outer sterile realm now increases
the attack of all party members by 40%
so outer is the first level of ultimate
and this will carry over to all Stell
realm basically just press ultimate
everybody gets 40% for 40 seconds this
is insane for S2 and for S3 casting
Liberation gives her 20 concerto energy
and this is really really good espe
eally when you're in a Time attack based
content like Tower where you need her to
outro ASAP so this one will facilitate
the whole uh switch rotation if you just
want pure output results just stop at S2
if you want to streamline your whole
switching uh rotation then stop at S3
now we look at S4 S4 is just 70%
additional healing from resonance skill
not very good S5 is the range of basic
attack three and isation is increased by
50% and 30% respectively so this is just
her pull her pulling AOE at S5 that's
why it's not very good at S6 increase
the damage multiplier of discernment by
42% and then casting discernment
increases the crit damage by 500% so
this makes her intro into a nuke so like
uh she's going to be doing like over
100k damage with no Buffs now you can
see for short keeper either stop at two
or three or six or zero if you
as for team composition short keeper is
similar to Vina healer so healer always
goes first in the team rotation and Then
followed by the second uh sub DPS and
Then followed by the third DPS so this
is just an example while I'm on this on
the topic of shke keeper and Verina Vina
is still not going away anytime soon so
Vina has smaller overall Buffs compared
to shke keeper however Verina has really
really fast outro speed like her
concerto gauge even more so if she's S2
and has variation they both have their
own uh strengths and weaknesses but yeah
that's about it for short keeper crash
course guide I hope this video has been
helpful to you in understanding short
keeper and how she works consider
leaving a comment subscribe to the
channel and I'll see you in the next
video bye-bye